Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
- I. Wolcott's Bound Volumes
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., March 16 - 31, 1799; (13 items) (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., April 1 - 15, 1799; (20 items) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., April 16 - 30, 1799; (15 items) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., May 1 - 15, 1799; (15 items) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., May 16 - 31, 1799; (21 items) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., June 1 - 10, 1799; (14 items) (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., June 11 - 20, 1799; (17 items) (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 36. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., June 21 - 30, 1799; (12 items) (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., July 1 - 15, 1799; (15 items) (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., July 16 - 31, 1779; (11 items) (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., August, 1799; (22 items) (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., September 1 - 16, 1799; (19 items) (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., Sept. 16 - 30, 1799; (19 items) (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., October, 1799; (13 items) (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., November, 1799; (17 items) (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., December, 1799; (9 items) (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., January, 1800; (10 items) (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., February, 1800; (19 items) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., March, 1800; (13 items) (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 37. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., April, 1800; (14 items) (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., May, 1800; (21 items) (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., June - July, 1800; (14 items) (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., August, 1800; (15 items) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., September 1 - 14, 1800; (14 items) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., September 15 - 30, 1800; (12 items) (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., October, 1800; (17 items) (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department; Account of Monies appropriated and expended by the state of New York for the Purpose of fortifying the Port and Harbour of New York (Aug. 28, 1799)., November, 1800; (16 items) (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 38. Drafts of letters from Treasury Department., December, 1800; (19 items) (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 39. Treasury Department circular letters., 1790 - 1794; (8 items) (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 39. Treasury Department circular letters., 1795; (5 items) (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 39. Treasury Department circular letters., 1796; (6 items) (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 39. Treasury Department circular letters., 1797; (8 items) (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 39. Treasury Department circular letters., 1798; (8 items) (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 39. Treasury Department circular letters., September 8, 1798; (1 item) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 39. Treasury Department circular letters., November, 1798 - 1800; (19 items) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., January - February, 1795; (5 items) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 40. Letters with supporting documents to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., February - May, 1795; (13 items) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., June - July, 1795; (5 items) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., September - December, 1795; (12 items) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., February, 1796; (12 items) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., March - June, 1796; (8 items) (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., July - December, 1796; (24 items) (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., January - August, 1797; (15 items) (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., September, 1797 - March 1798; (11 items) (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., April - July, 1798; (11 items) (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., September - December, 1798; (9 items) (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., January - June, 1799; (11 items) (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 40. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., July - October, 1799; (20 items) (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., (1 item) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., 1793; (4 items) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., 1794; (14 items) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., January - August, 1795; (8 items) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., September - December, 1795; (10 items) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., 1796; (9 items) (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., 1797; (7 items) (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials. (One item dated 1798.), 1797; (15 items) (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., 1798; (12 items) (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., 1799; (6 items) (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from international bankers and government officials., 1800; (6 items) (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to Treasury Department from John Quincy Adams., 1795; (11 items) (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 41. Letters and copies of letters to the Treasury Department from Thomas B. Adams and John Quincy Adams. One letter in French., 1796 - 1797; (11 items) (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 41. Letters to the Treasury Department from John Quincy Adams., 1797; (6 items) (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 41. Courier de Comerce et Maritime, Amsterdam; Rotterdamsche Courant. Six in French and one in Dutch., 1795 - 1796; (7 items) (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Reports and related correspondence., (5 items) (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Department Reports and related correspondence., January - June, 1796; (13 items) (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 42. Letter and report to the President of the United States from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., July - September, 1796; (2 items) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 42. Treasury Department reports and related documents and correspondence., January - April, 1797; (7 items) (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Department Reports., June - December, 1797; (3 items) (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Department Reports., January - August, 1798; (10 items) (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Department Reports and related correspondence., September - December, 1798; (15 items) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Department Reports and related correspondence., January - June, 1799; (8 items) (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Department Reports and related correspondence., July - September, 1799; (6 items) (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 42. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Treasury Department Reports and related correspondence., November, 1799; (5 items) (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 43. Drafts of confidential Treasury Department letters., November, 1794; (2 items) (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 43. Drafts of confidential Treasury Department letters., 1795; (6 items) (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 43. Drafts of confidential Treasury Department letters., 1796; (13 items) (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 43. Drafts of confidential Treasury Department letters., 1797 - February, 1798; (14 items) (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 43. Drafts of confidential Treasury Department letters., March - December, 1798; (22 items) (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 43. Drafts of confidential Treasury Department letters., 1799; (20 items) (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 43. Drafts of confidential Treasury Department letters., 1800; (6 items) (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., May - July, 1817; (21 items) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., July - October, 1817; (13 items) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., October - November, 1817; (15 items) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., October - December, 1817; (8 items) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., September, 1817 - January, 1818; (15 items) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut; resolutions of the General Assembly; Proclamations from His Excellency Oliver Wolcott, Governor and Commander in Chief in and over the State of Connecticut., 1817 - 1818; (12 items) (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., August 25, 1817 - February 11, 1818; (16 items) (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., February 14 - June 1, 1818; (19 items) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., June 2 - September 1, 1818; (17 items) (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 44. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., September - December, 1818; (19 items) (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 45. Letters (personal) to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1817; (17 items) (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 45. Letters (personal) to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., January - April, 1818; (14 items) (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 45. Letters (personal) to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; Proceedings of the Grand Lodge of Connecticut (May 20, 1818)., May - December, 1818; (7 items) (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 45. Letters (personal) and related material to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; Annual Report of the Keeper of the Penitentiary (October 30, 1818)., 1819; (15 items) (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., January - March, 1819; (17 items) (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut; An Act to provide for the Assessment and Collection of Taxes, in this State; An Act for ascertaining the residence of the owners of Bank Stock in this State, and for taxing non-residents; The Tax Bill; An Act for the Direction of Listers in their Office and Duty., 1817 - 1819; (16 items) (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., March - April, 1819; (13 items) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., May, 1819; (26 items) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., April - June, 1819; (15 items) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut; Copy of Speech, May Session., May - July, 1819; (15 items) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut. (One letter dated April, 1819.), August, 1819; (24 items) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 46. Letters and supporting documents to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., August - December, 1819; (24 items) (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 46. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., April - December, 1819; (16 items) (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; Proclamation by His Excellency Oliver Wolcott (February 25, 1820); Proceedings of the Grand Lodge of Connecticut (May 19, 1819)., 1816 - 1820; (24 items) (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1821; (21 items) (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., Dec. 31, 1821 - 1822; (11 items) (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1821 - 1822; (17 items) (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; letter to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning the Society for Propagating the Gospel among the Indians and others in North America and the Mohegan Tribe in Montville., 1822 - 1823; (22 items) (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1822 - 1823; (18 items) (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; list of School Societies in Connecticut., 1820 - 1822; (5 items) (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. primarily concerning political appointments., 1823; (19 items) (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Vol 47. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. The letters are primarily confidential and mainly concern the presidential election of 1824., October, 1823 - December, 1824; (20 items) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 47. Letters (confidential) to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1825; (17 items) (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 48. Letters and copies of letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs. (One in French.), 1783 - 1795; (14 items) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 48. Copies of letters from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1796 - 1797; (11 items) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1798 - 1803; (12 items) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs., January - May, 1804; (17 items) (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs., June - December, 1804; (7 items) (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1805 - 1807; (13 items) (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1808 - 1809; (15 items) (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and George Gibbs. Correspondents include Noah Webster and Robert Fulton. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1810 - 1815; (13 items) (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and George Gibbs. (One in French.) Items collected by George Gibbs., 1818 - 1821; (9 items) (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1823 - 1827; (9 items) (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 48. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; draft of Wolcott's essay concerning the claims of British creditors under the Treaty of Peace. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1828 - 1829; (6 items) (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 48. Constitution of Connecticut drafted by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1818; (1 item) (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 48. Copy of the proposed Constitution of Connecticut submitted by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1818; (1 items) (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 48. Notes and drafts of letters by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and George Gibbs., [18-?]; (4 items) (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 49. Speeches delivered before the General Assembly of Connecticut by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1817 - 1818; (8 items) (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Vol. 18. Speeches to the General Assembly by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1819; (2 items) (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Vol. 49. Copy of an Act Relating to Electors; Speeches to the General Assembly by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1820 - 1821; (4 items) (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Vol. 49. Speeches to the General Assembly by Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; An Act to protect the citizens of Connecticut in their right to navigate boats or vessels moved by Fire or Steam; Copy of the Governor's Message containing his reasons for not approving the Act., 1822; (4 items) (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 49. Speech to the General Assembly by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. One draft and one print version., 1823; (2 items) (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 49. Speech to the General Assembly by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. One draft and one print version., 1824; (2 items) (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 49. Speech to the General Assembly by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. One draft and one print version., 1825; (2 items) (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 49. Speech to the General Assembly by Oliver Wolcott, Jr. One draft and one print version., 1826; (2 items) (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut; a Proclamation concerning a day of Christian Fast., 1820; (24 items) (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut; letters concerning Newgate Prison and Native Americans., 1820 - 1822; (22 items) (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning Newgate Prison and the penitentiary system., 1819 - 1821; (9 items) (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., 1821; (4 items) (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning the preparation of flax., 1821 - 1823; (11 items) (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut; Proposals for Publishing, by Subscription, A Work Entitled The Vineyard; or The Art of Cultivating the Vine, and of Making Wine (printed)., 1822 - 1833; (12 items) (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., 1823 - 1824; (11 items) (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., 1821 - 1824; (21 items) (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut; Memorial of John Ross, George Lowrey, Major Ridge, and Elijah Hicks, Delegates from the Cherokee Nation of Indians (April 16, 1824)., (20 items) (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., 1824; (19 items) (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 50. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. during his tenure as Governor of Connecticut., 1824; (20 items) (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 51. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s draft of his Inaugural Address and a Proclamation., 1817; (3 items) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 51. Rough Draft of the Constitution of the State of Connecticut., 1818; (1 items) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 51. Drafts of messages, speeches, and proclamations by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1817 - 1820; (6 items) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 51. Rough Draft of a System of Taxation, by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1819; (1 item) (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 51. Rough Draft of [a] System of Taxation, by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1819; (1 item) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 51. Drafts of letters from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning slavery and the militia of the State of Connecticut., 1820 - 1826; (2 items) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 52. Letters to, from, and about Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Letters collected by George Gibbs., 1774; 1822 - 1837; (16 items) (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 52. Notes on the Wolcott family history; autobiographical narrative by Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; extract from a book in the possession of Erastus Wolcott; Wolcott family tree; letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning family history; Last Will and Testament of Fenn Wadsworth., 1783 - 1838; (15 items) (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 52. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning his nomination to office under the United States. Items collected by George Gibbs., 1789 - 1795; (15 items) (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 52. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and Colonel George Gibbs., 1812 - 1821; (15 items) (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 52. Letters to Oliver Wolcott, Jr., John S. Wolcott, and Colonel George Gibbs. Correspondents include John Quincy Adams and Henrietta (Edwards) Whitney (widow of Eli Whitney)., 1796 - 1834; (19 items) (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 53. Drafts of letters from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., December, 1803; (6 items) (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 53. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1803 - 1804; (14 items) (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 53. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; Articles of Agreement between Oliver Wolcott of Litchfield in the State of Connecticut and James Watson, Moses Rogers, Archibald Gracie, and William W. Woolsey of the City of New York...., 1802 - 1805; (16 items) (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 53. Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. concerning to establishment of Oliver Wolcott & Company., 1802 - 1803; (19 items) (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 54. Letters to Laura (Lorrain) Wolcott and Elizabeth Stoughton Wolcott., 1759 - 1798; (4 items) (Box 29, Folder 16)
- II. Correspondence
  - Copies of letters to Dr. Edward Stevens from Alexander Hamilton; copy of letter to Matthew Griswold from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1769 - 1772; (3 items) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1786 - 1788; (9 items) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr.; letters to Elisa Wolcott., 1789 - 1793; (12 items) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1794; (5 items) (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Letters to and from Oliver Wolcott, Jr. and Jeremiah Wadsworth, Alexander Hamilton, Elisa Wolcott, David Henley, and Frederick Wolcott., 1795; (10 items) (Box 30, Folder 5)